Sparkling Wine Is In Its Prime.
起泡酒正迎来它的黄金时期。
Here Are Five Bottles To Savor.
这里有五款值得细细品味的起泡酒。
New varieties beyond traditional Champagnes and Proseccos are inviting drinkers to reconsider bubbles.
除了传统的香槟和普罗赛克起泡酒之外，新品种正吸引消费者重新认识起泡酒。
Some might associate sparkling wine mostly with special occasions, like wedding toasts or New Year's Eve.
有些人可能主要把起泡酒与特殊场合联系在一起，比如婚礼祝酒或新年前夜。
Others may think of their favorite spritz—whether Aperol, Campari or Hugo.
还有一些人会想到自己最喜欢的 Spritz 鸡尾酒，无论是 Aperol、Campari 还是 Hugo。
But recently, a proliferation of sparkling wines beyond the usual Champagnes, Cavas, Crémants and Proseccos has burnished the beverage's reputation as one to enjoy on its own, on any day of the year.
但近年来，除了传统的香槟、卡瓦、Crémant 和普罗赛克之外，各类起泡酒大量涌现，使起泡酒逐渐树立起一种新的声誉——它本身就值得品尝，而且一年中的任何一天都适合饮用。
"I know people who are not in the industry that drink bubbles every day," said Tonya Pitts, a sommelier in San Francisco. "
我认识一些并非业内人士的人，他们每天都会喝起泡酒。"旧金山侍酒师 Tonya Pitts 说道。
"It's so accessible now and people are drinking more of it." "
如今它变得非常容易获得，人们喝得也越来越多了。"
As consumption of wine and spirits writ large has been in steady decline, sparkling wine has maintained, well, its sparkle—outperforming other categories with carbonated verve.
随着葡萄酒和烈酒整体消费持续下降，起泡酒却依然保持着自己的"光彩"——凭借充满活力的气泡感，表现优于其他品类。
The global sparkling wine market has continued to grow, reaching nearly $50 billion in 2025, according to analysis from Maximize Market Research, a firm that tracks industry trends.
根据市场研究机构 Maximize Market Research（专门追踪行业趋势）的分析，全球起泡酒市场持续增长，2025 年市场规模已接近 500 亿美元。
Its projections show the sparkling wine market expanding to about $69 billion by 2032.
该机构预测，到 2032 年，全球起泡酒市场将扩大至约 690 亿美元。
The drink's evolution has included more sparkling wines made with red wine grapes, such as Pinot Noir and Cabernet Franc.
起泡酒的发展趋势之一，是越来越多采用红葡萄品种（如黑皮诺和品丽珠）酿造起泡酒。
"If the varietal can be grown and produced to have enough acidity on its own without having to add acidity to change the structure of your end product, it can be used to produce sparkling wine," Pitts explained.
Pitts解释说："如果某种葡萄品种本身就能培育出足够的酸度，而无需额外添加酸来改变最终产品的结构，那么它就可以用来酿造起泡酒。"
More sparkling wines are now also sold at stores not typically associated with specialty beverages, like Aldi and Costco.
如今，越来越多的起泡酒也开始出现在一些原本并不以专业酒类著称的商店里，例如 Aldi 和 Costco。
With people drinking less, many are opting for bottles that feel more special—
随着人们饮酒量减少，越来越多人开始选择那些更具"特别感"的酒款——
whether from a small producer, a sustainable vineyard or, increasingly, a category long associated with celebration and quality.
无论是来自小型酒庄、可持续经营的葡萄园，还是越来越受到青睐、长期与庆祝和高品质联系在一起的起泡酒。